Guide to the Civil War Stereographs 1861-1865 PR 65-1
New-York Historical Society
- Straw huts erected on Smith's farm, and used as a hospital after the battle of Antietam., 1862 (Item 788-34)
  Straw huts erected in a field on Smith's farm, and used as a hospital after the battle of Antietam.
- Burnside bridge. South-Eastern view., 1862 (Item 788-35)
  Burnside bridge. South-Eastern view.
- Burnside bridge, from the South-East., 1862 (Item 788-36)
  Burnside bridge, from the South-East.
- Bridge across the Antietam. North-East view., 1862 (Item 788-37)
  Bridge across the Antietam. North-East view with houses and barns in the background.
- Signal tower on Elk Mountain, overlooking battle field of Antietam., 1862 (Item 788-38)
  Soldiers on top of signal tower on Elk Mountain, overlooking battle field of Antietam.
- View of battle field of Antietam on day of battle, 17th September, 1862. (Item 788-39)
  View of battle field of Antietam on day of battle, 17th September, 1862.
- Dunker Church, Antietam, Sept. 17th 1862., 1862, published later (Item 788-40)
  Dead soldiers with cart and church in background.
- The "Sunken Road" at Antietam., 1862, published later (Item 788-41)
  Soldiers dead in the ditch or "sunken road."
- The "Sunken Road" at Antietam., 1862, published later (Item 788-42)
- Where Sumner's Corps charged at Antietam., 1862, published later (Item 788-43)
  View on battle field of Antietam where Sumner's corps charged the enemy. Dead soldiers litter the battle field.
- Where Sumner's Corps charged at Antietam., 1862, published later (Item 788-44)
- On the Antietam Battlefield., 1862, published later (Item 788-45)
  This is a view of the west side of the Hagerstown Road. The bodies of the dead are next to a wooden fence.
- Burnside Bridge, Antietam, Sept., 1862., 1862, published later (Item 788-46)
  Burnside Bridge, Antietam, Sept., 1862, from above.
- Burnside Bridge, Antietam, Sept., 1862., 1862, published later (Item 788-47)
- Battle Grounds of the Potomac Valley., after 1868? (Item 788-48)
  Large gathering of people for Memorial Day observance at Antietam.
- The levee at Vicksburg, Miss., February, 1864., 1864, published later (Item 789-1)
  The Vicksburg levee with steamboats.
- New York's famous 7th Regiment leaving for the war Apr. 1865 [1861?] (Item 790-1)
  Crowds of people lined up along the street watching the soldiers preparing to leave for the war.
- Military on Broadway., 1865 (Item 790-2)
  Military marching on Broadway with onlookers.
- Broadway from Barnum's Museum, showing portion of park barracks., ca.1861 (Item 790-3)
  Civil War barracks in City Hall Park, traffic and pedestrians.
- [New York 7th Regiment marching down the street.], ca.1861-ca.1865 (Item 790-4)
  New York 7th Regiment marching down the street.
- Procession while organizing on Broadway and Canal St., ca.1861-ca.1865 (Item 790-5)
  Soldiers marching down Broadway in New York City with crowds of on lookers.
- The crowd gathering about the Equestrian Statue of Washington. The Everett House in the distance., 1861 (Item 791-1)
  The crowd gathering about the Equestrian Statue of Washington. Union Square in middle ground, Everett House in the distance.
- The great union meeting in Union Square, New- York, April 20, 1861. (Item 791-2)
  The crowd gathering about the Equestrian Statue of Washington, the Everett House in the distance.
- The gathering numbers fill the streets and crown the house tops with a crowds of civilians., 1861 (Item 791-3)
  The streets and house tops crowded with people, American flags flying from roof-tops, above Union Square.
- Mass meeting in N.Y., Apr. 20, 1861 (Item 791-4)
  The streets and house tops crowded with civilians, American flags flying from roof-tops, above Union Square.
- The dense mass gathered around one of the Speaker's stands, over which gracefully floats the Stars and Stripes, 1861 (Item 791-5)
  Dense group of people listening to a speaker, large flag above them.
- The great union meeting in Union Square, New- York, April 20, 1861, flag of Fort Sumter, left. (Item 791-6)
- The equestrian statue of Washington, bearing aloft the Flag of Fort Sumter, a great historical picture. Below see the heaving mass burning with devotion to the Constitution bequeathed to them as a sacred legacy by their fathers., 1861 (Item 791-7)
  The equestrian statue of Washington at Union Square with the flag of Fort Sumter and a crowd of people listening to a speaker.
- The great union meeting in Union Square, New-York, April 20, 1861. (Item 791-8)
  The equestrian statue of Washington, bearing aloft the flag of Fort Sumter. Crowd of people listening to a speaker.
- N. Y. City & Vicinity. [Rally in Union Square], ca.1861-ca.1865 (Item 791-9)
- English Armstrong gun in Fort Fisher, N. C., ca.1861-ca.1865, published later (Item 792-1)
  Armstrong gun in Fort Fisher with soldiers.
- Confederate soldiers and breastworks., 1863, published later (Item 793-1)
  Three soldiers seated on a pile of wood.
- The harvest of death., 1863 (Item 793-2)
  Dead soldiers lying on the battlefield.
- Breastworks on the left wing, battle of Gettysburgh., 1863 (Item 793-3)
  Two soldiers seated near the breastworks at Gettysburg.
- Position of the centre of the Army at Gettysburgh., 1863 (Item 793-4)
  Looking down on battlefield from rocky prominence at Gettysburg.
- Breastworks on the left wing, battle of Gettysburgh., 1863 (Item 793-5)
  Man peering over rock breastwork at Gettysburg.
- Cemetery gate, Gettysburgh., 1863 (Item 793-6)
  Gate of the Evergreen Cemetery, Gettysburg.
- Woods on the left wing, battle of Gettysburgh; in the middle ground a dead soldier., 1863 (Item 793-7)
  Woods on the left wing, battle of Gettysburg; in the middle ground a dead soldier.
- Wheat field, where Gen. Reynolds was killed., 1863 (Item 793-8)
  Wheat field, lined with fence, pond at right, where General John Reynolds was killed.
- Gen. R. E. Lee's headquarters, Gettysburgh., 1863 (Item 793-9)
  Gen. R. E. Lee's headquarters, Gettysburg.
- Gen. Mead's headquarters, Gettysburgh., 1863 (Item 793-10)
  Gen. Mead's headquarters, Gettysburg.
- Confederate prisoners, Gettysburg., 1863, published later (Item 793-11)
  Confederate prisoners seated on a pile of wood.
- All the live stock on Mr. Gill's plantation after the battle of Gettysburgh., 1863 (Item 793-12)
  African American man and children and a donkey near Gettysburg.
- Round Top Mountain, Gettysburgh., 1863 (Item 793-13)
  Man sitting behind stone fence or breastwork on Round Top.
- Round Top Mountain, Gettysburgh., 1863 (Item 793-14)
- Sugar Loaf Mountain, Gettysburgh., 1863 (Item 793-15)
  Two men riding in a wagon, one possibly Mathew Brady, with Sugar Loaf Mountain beyond.
- John L. Burns' cottage at Gettysburg, 1863 (Item 793-16)
  John L. Burns' cottage at Gettysburg, Burns on porch, woman in doorway.
- The test that tries men's souls, Battle of Gettysburg., 1863 (Item 793-17)
  Painting depicting Battle of Gettysburg.
- Scene in a wheat field on the Confederate right, at the battle of Gettysburg., 1863 (Item 793-18)
  Dead soldiers in a wheat field.
- Farmers' Inn and hotel, Emmittsburg, where our special artist was captured, July 5th, 1863. (Item 793-19)
  Three people seated on the front porch of the hotel at Emmittsburg.
- All over now- Confederate sharp-shooter at foot of Round Top, Gettysburg., 1863 (Item 793-20)
  Confederate sharp-shooter dead on top of rocks.
- Gateway of cemetery, Gettysburg., 1863 (Item 793-21)
  Gateway of Evergreen Cemetery, Gettysburg.
- Unfinished Confederate grave near the center of battle-field of Gettysburg., 1863 (Item 793-22)
  Several Confederate dead in shallow grave, wagon in the background.
- Unfinished Confederate grave near the center of battle-field of Gettysburg., 1863 (Item 793-23)
- Federal soldiers as they fell, at battle of Gettysburg., 1863 (Item 793-24)
  Fallen Federal soldiers on battlefield at Gettysburg.
- Confederate soldiers as they fell, near the centre of the battle-field of Gettysburg., 1863 (Item 793-25)
  Confederate soldiers near the center of the battlefield of Gettysburg where they died.
- Confederate soldiers who had evidently been shelled by our batteries on Round Top, at the battle of Gettysburg., 1863 (Item 793-26)
  Confederate soldiers who had been killed by artillery on Round Top, at the battle of Gettysburg.
- The home of a Rebel sharp-shooter, on battlefield of Gettysburg., 1863 (Item 793-27)
  The hiding place of a Confederate sharp-shooter, on battlefield of Gettysburg.
- View in wheat-field opposite our extreme left at battle of Gettysburg., 1863 (Item 793-28)
  Dead soldiers in a wheat field at Gettysburg.
- View in wheat-field opposite our extreme left at battle of Gettysburg., 1863 (Item 793-29)
- Evidence of how severe the contest had been on the right at the battle of Gettysburg., 1863 (Item 793-30)
  Dead soldiers scattered across a field.
- Dead sharp-shooter on the right of the Confederate line., 1863 (Item 793-31)
  Dead sharp-shooter on the right of the Confederate line.
- A harvest of death on the battle-field of Gettysburg., 1863 (Item 793-32)
  Union dead laid out on the battlefield.
- Scene in the woods at foot of Round Top, at battle of Gettysburg., 1863 (Item 793-33)
  Dead soldiers in the woods.
- View in slaughter pen, foot of Round Top, Gettysburg., 1863 (Item 793-34)
  Dead soldiers on the ground.
- Scene in the woods at slaughter pen., 1863 (Item 793-35)
  Dead soldiers among the trees.
- View on the left, on the battle field of Gettysburg., 1863 (Item 793-36)
- A Confederate sharp-shooter, who had been killed by a shell at battle of Gettysburg., 1863 (Item 793-37)
  Dead Confederate soldier next to rock.
- Gen. Meade's headquarters during the battle of Gettysburg., 1863 (Item 793-38)
  House with picket fence near a dirt road used as General Meade's headquarters.
- Slaughter pen on left wing at battle of Gettysburg., 1863 (Item 793-39)
  Soldier on rocky hillside, dead soldiers among the rocks
- Dead Confederate sharp shooter at the battle of Gettysburg., 1863 (Item 793-40)
  Dead Confederate sharp shooter, cap and rifle on ground beside him.
- Dead Confederate sharp shooter at the battle of Gettysburg., 1863 (Item 793-41)
- View of Slaughter Pen at battle of Gettysburg., 1863 (Item 793-42)
  View of dead soldiers on rocky hillside at battle of Gettysburg.
- View at Losser's [Trostle's] barn, where the 9th Massachusetts battery was cut up., 1863 (Item 793-43)
  View at Trostle's farm with dead horses in the foreground.
- View near the [Em]mittsburg road on battle-field [of] Gettysburg, 1863 (Item 793-44)
  Dead soldiers with covered wagon in the distance.
- War effect of a shell on a Confederate soldier at battle of Gettysburg., 1863 (Item 793-45)
  Dead Confederate soldier in a field, rifle with bayonet laying across his body
- Second artillery and 19th Massachusetts column, Battle of Gettysburg, U.S.A. (Item 793-46)
  Artist rendition of the second artillery and 19th Massachusetts column, Battle of Gettysburg.
- Gen. Meade's headquarters from cemetery., 1863 (Item 793-47)
  Gen. Meade's headquarters from cemetery.
- House of Gen. James Gettys, founder of Gettysburg., ca.1861-ca.1865, published later (Item 793-48)
  House of Gen. James Gettys, founder of Gettysburg.
- Gen. Meade's headquarters., ca.1861-ca.1865, published later (Item 793-49)
  Gen. Meade's headquarters.
- Battle field of Gettysburg- Gen. Lee's headquarters on the Chambersburg turnpike, west of Gettysburg., ca.1861-ca.1865 (Item 793-50)
  Gen. Lee's headquarters on the Chambersburg turnpike, west of Gettysburg.
- Southern portion of Gettysburg, from a position West of the town, near the Theological Seminary. Culp's Hill in the distance, on the right., ca.1861-ca.1865 (Item 793-51)
  Southern portion of Gettysburg, from west of the town near the Theological Seminary, road leading to town, and Culp's Hill in the distance, on the right.
- Battle field of Gettysburg- residence of John L. Burns on Chambersburg street., ca.1861-ca.1865 (Item 793-52)
  Residence of John L. Burns on Chambersburg street.
- Wheeler's New York Battery coming into action, battle of Gettysburg, U.S.A., 1863, published later (Item 793-53)
  Artist rendition of artillery unit with caissons entering the battle of Gettysburg.
- On the battlefield at Gettysburg., ca.1861-ca.1865, published later (Item 793-54)
  Group of Union soldiers dead on the battle field, soldiers looking on.
- Union dead at Gettysburg., 1863, published later (Item 793-55)
- The slaughter pen at Gettysburg., 1863, published later (Item 793-56)
  Dead soldiers at the slaughter pen at Gettysburg.
- General Meade's headquarters at Gettysburg., ca.1861-ca.1865, published later (Item 793-57)
- In Trossel's [Trostle's] barnyard, Gettysburg., 1863, published later (Item 793-58)
- In Trossel's [Trostle's] barnyard, Gettysburg., 1863, published later (Item 793-59)
- Three "Johnnie Reb" prisoners., 1863, published later (Item 793-60)
  Three Confederate prisoners seated on planks of wood.
- Part of interior of Fort Walker, Port Royal., ca.1861-ca.1865 (Item 794-1)
  Wood bracing the masonry fortifications, with cannon above, and laundry hanging from lines below.
- [Fort Wagner, Folly Island, South Carolina], ca.1861-ca.1865 (Item 794-2)
  Fortification, possibly Fort Wagner on Folly Island, with cannon in foreground, piles of shot beyond.
- Ordinance [sic] yard, Morris Island near Charleston, S.C. (Item 794-3)
  Cannons and other ordnance at Morris Island, South Carolina.
- Slave quarters Smith's plantation, Port Royal., ca.1862 (Item 794-4)
  House with African Americans seated in front, Smith's plantation, Port Royal.
- Preparing cotton for the gin., 1862 (Item 794-5)
  African Americans outside a building preparing cotton for the cotton gin, possibly at Smith's plantation, Port Royal.
- Slaves preparing cotton for gin., ca.1862 (Item 794-6)
- Interior of Ft. Wagner, Morris Island, S.C., showing officers' quarters., 1863 (Item 794-7)
  Interior of Ft. Wagner, Morris island, S.C., showing tents on platforms that serve as officers' quarters.
- 300 pound Parrot Gun, in Ft. Chatfield, Morris Island, S.C., 1863 (Item 794-8)
  300 pound Parrott Gun, named after a Col. Brayton, with soldiers ready to fire it.
- Garrison of Fort Wagner on parade., 1863, published later (Item 794-9)
  Garrison of Fort Wagner on parade, tents and fortification in background.
- A battery of "Quaker guns.", ca.1861-ca.1865, published later, published later (Item 794-10)
  Soldiers with rifles standing guard over decoy cannons made of logs mounted to wheels.
- "Mounting Guard" in Fort Wagner, Morris Island, S.C., 1863?, published later (Item 794-11)
  Soldiers in formation, mounting guard in Fort Wagner, Morris Island, S.C.
- The Parrot Rifled Cannon that threw the shot and shell in Charleston, S.C., from Morris Island., 1863 (Item 794-12)
  Parrott rifled cannons that shelled Charleston, S.C., from Morris Island, lined up under some trees.
- Interior view of Ft. Putnam, Charleston Harbor, S.C., 1863 (Item 794-13)
  Interior view of Fort Putnam, Charleston Harbor, S.C. with piles of cannonballs.
- North east angle of Ft. Marshall, Sullivan Island, Charleston Harbor, S.C., 1863 (Item 794-14)
  Cannons on the parapet of Fort Marshall, Sullivan Island, Charleston Harbor, S.C.
- The famous "swamp angel" gun; throws rifled shell into Charleston night and day., 1863, published later (Item 794-15)
  Soldiers with the "Swamp Angel" gun.
- Wreck of the original Swamp Angel, the first gun that fired on Charleston., 1863 (Item 794-16)
  Wreck of the original Swamp Angel, the first gun that fired on Charleston, soldiers in boat in the background.
- Possibly Hilton Head, ca. 1864 (Item 794-17)
  Fortifications, buildings and small cabins in a flat landscape.
- Soldiers Cemetery, Beaufort, S. C., ca.1861-ca.1865 (Item 795-1)
  Tomb stones at Soldiers Cemetery, Beaufort, South Carolina.
- Arsenal, Beaufort, S. C., ca.1861-ca.1865 (Item 795-2)
  Arsenal building behind high white wall, Beaufort, S.C.
- C[amp] G[round], 2nd U.S. Art[iller]y Colored, Beaufort, S.C., ca. 1864 (Item 795-3)
  African American men of Battery G, 2nd Light Artillery standing at attention near tents and artillery pieces, Beaufort, S.C.
- Ordnance Office, Beaufort, S. C., 1864 (Item 795-4)
  Ordnance Office with soldiers on the porch, possibly including Capt. H.L. Ryce, Ordnance officer, 76th Pennsylvania Volunteers, Beaufort, S. C.
- Hospital No. 3, Beaufort, S. C., ca.1861-ca.1865 (Item 795-5)
  Hospital No. 3, Beaufort, S. C., shot straight on showing deep verandas on both floors of the building.
- Hospital #5, Beauford [Beaufort], S. C., 1864 (Item 795-6)
  Hospital building in Beaufort, S. C., a large house that has been converted.
- Hospital #7, Beauford [Beaufort], S. C. formerly owned by Edgar Tripp, Esq., Janry 1864 (Item 795-7)
  Hospital building in Beaufort, S. C.
- Hospital #8, Beauford [Beaufort], S. C., ca.1861-ca.1865 (Item 795-8)
- Hospital #9, Beaufort, S. C., 1864 (Item 795-9)
  House with large verandas on three sides, and low fence in front, Hospital #9, Beaufort, S. C.
- Sanitary Commission, Beaufort, S. C., ca.1861-ca.1865 (Item 795-10)
  Large house surrounded by a fence with sign over the gate for the U.S. Sanitary Commission.
- Beaufort, S. C. 1862, boat landing. (Item 795-11)
  Boat landing with houses in the back ground and African Americans, right.
- Capt. Jno. H. Moore's residence, Post Quarter Master. March 1864, Beaufort, S. C. (Item 795-12)
  House with a group of people standing on the porch.
- [Post] Chaplin's [sic] residence, Beaufort, S.C., ca. 1864 (Item 795-13)
- Signal station, Beaufort, S. C., 1864 (Item 795-14)
  House with superstructure built atop it for use as a signal station, Beaufort, S.C.
- Signal station at Beaufort, S. C., Feb. 1862. Once the residence of J. G. Barnwell (adjoining hqts.. General Stevens, right.) (Item 795-15)
  Signal station at Beaufort, S. C., Feb. 1862 soldier standing on superstructure built atop house, next to General Isaac Stevens' headquarters just visible, right.
- Signal station at Beaufort, S. C., Feb. 1862 next to Gen. Steven's Hdqts. (Item 795-16)
  Soldiers on horseback in the street in front of the signal station and Gen. Isaac Stevens headquarters.
- Head Quarters, 115th N.Y., Beaufort, S.C. Col. Sammons, March 1864 (Item 795-17)
  Looking over picket fence across yard toward small house housing the Headquarters of the 115th N.Y. Infantry.
- Camp of 8th Maine, Beaufort, S.C., 1864 (Item 795-18)
  Camp tents of the 8th Maine Infantry Regiment at Beaufort, South Carolina.
- Adjt. General's office, Beaufort, S.C., 1864 (Item 795-19)
  Sentry and other soldiers in front of house used as office, Beaufort, S.C.
- Beebe's quarters, ca. 1863 (Item 795-20)
  Large house with verandas and fence, sentry at top of stairs, Beaufort, S.C.
- Tyler's Store, Bay St., Beaufort, S.C. opposite Post Office, during the passage of Sherman's Army, 1864 (Item 795-21)
  Soldiers out front, and wagons alongside a store in Beaufort, S.C.
- Dr. Clyman's, Chief Medical Officer, March 1864, Beaufort, S.C. (Item 795-22)
  Two soldiers outside the gate of a large house used by Dr. Clyman.
- Ball room, 22 Febry, 1864, Beaufort, S.C. (Item 795-23)
  Large room decorated with bunting and swags, and a banner for Washington's birthday.
- Ball room, 22 Febry, 1864, Beaufort, S.C. (Item 795-24)
  View of ballroom decorated for Washington's birthday with bunting, swags, an American flag, with settees lining it.
- Issuing stores to contrabands, Beaufort, S.C., ca. 1863 (Item 795-25)
  African Americans outside building, with European Americans on steps.
- The ruins of Charleston, S.C., showing the sister churches., ca. 1861 (Item 796-1)
  The ruins of Charleston, S.C., showing the churches in the background with rubble in foreground.
- The ruins of Charleston, S.C., showing the sister churches., ca. 1861 (Item 796-2)
- Meeting St., near Broad, Charleston, S.C., looking north. St. Michael's church in the middle distance., ca. 1861-ca. 1865 (Item 796-3)
  Meeting St., near Broad, Charleston, S.C., looking north, St. Michael's church in the middle distance.
- Group of relics in Charleston, S.C., arsenal, showing Rebel torpedoes, shot, shell, and breach of the 600 lb. Blakely Gun., ca. 1865 (Item 796-4)
  Man sitting among items in Charleston, S.C., arsenal, including Confederate torpedoes, shot, shell, and breach of the 600 lb. Blakely Gun.
- View on the battery, Charleston, S.C. remains of the large Blakely gun, burst by the rebels before the evacuation., 1865 (Item 796-5)
  View on the battery, Charleston, S.C. remains of the large Blakely gun, in front of a large home, burst by the Confederates before the evacuation.
- South Battery, Charleston, S.C., looking N.E. ruins of Blakely Gun in the foreground., ca. 1865 (Item 796-6)
  South Battery, Charleston, S.C., looking N.E. ruins of Blakely Gun in the foreground, along with protective earthworks, houses and street beyond.
- Ruins of the North Eastern Depot, Charleston, S.C. blown up at the time of the evacuation by the Rebels., ca. 1865 (Item 796-7)
  Arched façade and rubble, remains of the North Eastern Depot, Charleston, S.C. blown up at the time of the evacuation by the Confederates.
- Panoramic view, the ruins of Charleston, S.C., Roman Catholic Cathedral in the distance., ca. 1861 (Item 796-8)
  Boy sits atop steps among the ruins of Charleston, S.C., Roman Catholic Cathedral in the background.
- Broad St., Charleston, S.C., looking East with the ruins of the Roman Catholic Cathedral and St. Michael's church in the distance., ca. 1861 (Item 796-9)
  Broad St., Charleston, S.C., looking East with the arched façade and towers of the Roman Catholic Cathedral, and St. Michael's church in the distance.
- Meeting St., Charleston, S.C. looking South, ca.1861 (Item 796-10)
  Street in Charleston, S.C., probably after the fire of 1861.
- The old Post Office at the junction of East Bay and Broad St., Charleston, S.C., showing the only palmetto tree in the city, ca. 1865 (Item 796-11)
  Post office on the right, palmetto on sidewalk to left.
- The old Market House, junction of Market and Meeting St., Charleston, S.C., ca. 1865 (Item 796-12)
  The old Market House, with steps with ironwork in front.
- The old Market House, junction of Market and Meeting St., Charleston, S. C., ca. 1865 (Item 796-13)
- Ruins of North Eastern R.R. depot where 200 persons were blown up on the day of the evacuation, Charleston, S.C., 1863 (Item 796-14)
- Ruins of Circular Church and Secession Hall., ca. 1861 (Item 796-15)
  Ruins of Circular Church and Secession Hall, with only columns and walls standing.
- Ruins of St. Finbars, 1863 (Item 796-16)
  Church, probably after fire in Charleston, South Carolina, 1861.
- Institute Hall, where on Dec. 20, 1860 the Ordinance of Secession was ratified., before 1861 (Item 796-17)
  Institute Hall, where on Dec. 20, 1860 the Ordinance of Secession was ratified next door to the Teetotal Restaurant and Circular Church.
- Panoramic view of Charleston, from the spire of St. Michael's Church (looking north.), ca.1860 (Item 796-18)
  Panoramic view of Charleston, from the spire of St. Michael's Church (looking north).
- After the fire of 1861, Circular Church, Meeting Street, Charleston S.C. (Item 796-19)
  Heavily damaged street with Circular Church on the right side of the road.
- Point Battery, junction of East and South Battery Streets., 1865 (Item 796-20)
  Artillery at Point Battery, junction of East and South Battery Streets, baskets in the foreground.
- Commercial wharf battery., 1865 (Item 796-21)
  Commercial wharf battery, with wharf in the foreground, and earthworks in front of buildings.
- Ruins of North Eastern Depot, blown up during the evacuation of Charleston (about 300 lives lost.), 1865 (Item 796-22)